<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Locus: Richard Careaga</title>
    <link>/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Locus: Richard Careaga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathan Yau on the challenges of thematic maps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/09/nathan-yau-on-the-challenges-of-thematic-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/09/nathan-yau-on-the-challenges-of-thematic-maps/</guid>
      <description>If you are a paying member of Flowing Data (well worth the modest subscription), you will have received his email, reproduce at a paywalled portion of [Flowing Data].
He gives a detailed critique of a precinct-by-precinct map of the 2016 presidential election, nationwide, showing the number of votes for Trump and Clinton and the nearest precinct in which the opposing candidate was in the majority.
He compares what the map purports to show with what it actually does show, which is the raw total of votes (ho-hum, we&amp;rsquo;ve known that for a long time) and the percentages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newtonian Data Science</title>
      <link>/2018/08/04/newtonian-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/04/newtonian-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Most advanced machine learning and AI strike me as deterministic finite state machines with an error term. Properly tuned, the same input should produce much the same output every time. Like Newtonian physics, they can be complicated, but deconstructible into simple components. Like Newtonian physics, as well, they are highly accurate and reliable within their domain.
What happens when we start applying the same tools to complex systems? What are the complex systems of importance that refuse to yield identical results with identical inputs?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>