<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Locus: Richard Careaga</title>
    <link>/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Locus: Richard Careaga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The plural of data science is not formulae</title>
      <link>/2018/08/14/the-plural-of-data-science-is-not-formulae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/14/the-plural-of-data-science-is-not-formulae/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ report of academic research on career hot streaks has snagged a lot of LinkedIn eyeballs today (Career &amp;lsquo;hot steaks&amp;rsquo; are real 1h ago • 3,526 readers).
Reading the paper (https://goo.gl/2Mwqjn), you can see that it is an observational study of a convenience sample (these were the people about whom data were available, in the thousands or tens of thousands, an impressive collection).
Two mysteries: Why were the data not stratified into a training set and a test set?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newtonian Data Science</title>
      <link>/2018/08/04/newtonian-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/04/newtonian-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Most advanced machine learning and AI strike me as deterministic finite state machines with an error term. Properly tuned, the same input should produce much the same output every time. Like Newtonian physics, they can be complicated, but deconstructible into simple components. Like Newtonian physics, as well, they are highly accurate and reliable within their domain.
What happens when we start applying the same tools to complex systems? What are the complex systems of importance that refuse to yield identical results with identical inputs?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>