<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on Locus: Richard Careaga</title>
    <link>/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on Locus: Richard Careaga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Row collapsing</title>
      <link>/2019/05/03/duplicate-keys-for-multiple-logical-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/03/duplicate-keys-for-multiple-logical-columns/</guid>
      <description>Untidy happens It’s not always possible to store everything in a tidy but humongous data store. So, we have things like SQL foreign keys.
Unfortunately, the database may not have been set up with future tidy in mind. Or, database access is only provided through CSV files.
Here’s an example of what can happen. We begin with some basic information, as tidy as we could wish with not too much effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The compiler will tell you what the user cannot</title>
      <link>/2019/01/08/the-compiler-will-tell-you-what-the-user-cannot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/08/the-compiler-will-tell-you-what-the-user-cannot/</guid>
      <description>The compiler will always tell you about source code errors that prevent compiling. It can’t advise you if your code solves the problem that it was supposed to solve, even if you are confident in what that problem is. But have a thought for the user who posed the problem, and keep in mind two famous quotations.
 Thus, programs must be executed for humans to read, only incidentially for machines to execute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Month arithmetic in R, a quick guide</title>
      <link>/2018/10/20/month-arithmetic-in-r-a-quick-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/20/month-arithmetic-in-r-a-quick-guide/</guid>
      <description>Here are questions you might want to ask about months: How many more months until September 1? months_to How many more calendar months until September 1? cal_months_to How many months between this month and September 1? months_between How many more calendar months between this month and September 1? cal_months_between In how many calendar months must I wait until September 1? months_inclusive  Assume we are asking the question on February 1 of a non-leap year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive styles of data science</title>
      <link>/2018/09/10/cognitive-styles-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/10/cognitive-styles-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Yihui Xie of RMarkdown fame has a long, thoughtful post (https://goo.gl/WjA7t8) on a debate for and against working in various types of interactive notebooks, such as Juypter for the Python platform, IDEs like RStudio in its so-called “notebook mode” and the old school heavy code commenting, among other approaches. Although that’s the primary subject, he weaves in some astute observations of the differences among “data scientists” based on whether their perspective grows from data origins or is aimed at ultimately producing software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newtonian Data Sciences</title>
      <link>/2018/08/06/newtonian-data-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/06/newtonian-data-sciences/</guid>
      <description>Advanced machine learning and AI strike me as deterministic finite state machines with an error term. Properly tuned, the same input should produce much the same output every time. Like Newtonian physics, they can be complicated, but deconstructible into simple components. Like Newtonian physics, as well, they are highly accurate and reliable within their domain.
What happens when we start applying the same tools to complex systems? What are the complex systems of importance that refuse to yield identical results with identical inputs?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>