<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geospatial on Locus: Richard Careaga</title>
    <link>https://technocrat.rbind.io/tags/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geospatial on Locus: Richard Careaga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://technocrat.rbind.io/tags/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Map Atlas for Continuously Scaled Maps</title>
      <link>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/12/03/color-map-atlas-for-continuously-scaled-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/12/03/color-map-atlas-for-continuously-scaled-maps/</guid>
      <description>## Please note: Alaska and Hawaii are being shifted and are not to scale. ## Getting data from the 2012-2016 5-year ACS ## Parsed with column specification: ## cols( ## NAME = col_character(), ## Q22018_GDP = col_double() ## ) Color, Design and Communication Graphic design standards, especially for color, are an official Good Thing. Branding, visual cueing, consistency. Map colors are hard, especially when dealing with continuous data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unbearable Lightness of Coloring Maps</title>
      <link>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/08/31/the-unbearable-lightness-of-coloring-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/08/31/the-unbearable-lightness-of-coloring-maps/</guid>
      <description>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has lead responsibilities for protecting the United States against domestic crimes initiated abroad. These responsibilities include protection against “covert actions by foreign governments to influence U.S. political sentiment or public discourse” (https://www.fbi.gov/investigate/counterintelligence/foreign-influence). It has illustrated its mission description with a world map that appears to classify nations by the threats they pose.
The map has no description or legend, but uses several shades of blue to distinguish among countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathan Yau on the challenges of thematic maps</title>
      <link>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/08/09/nathan-yau-on-the-challenges-of-thematic-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://technocrat.rbind.io/2018/08/09/nathan-yau-on-the-challenges-of-thematic-maps/</guid>
      <description>If you are a paying member of Flowing Data (well worth the modest subscription), you will have received his email, reproduced at a paywalled portion of the site.
He gives a detailed critique of a precinct-by-precinct map of the 2016 presidential election, nationwide, showing the number of votes for Trump and Clinton and the nearest precinct in which the opposing candidate was in the majority.
He compares what the map purports to show with what it actually does show, which is the raw total of votes (ho-hum, we’ve known that for a long time) and the percentages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>